Digital & Al Product Delivery Manager with 13+ years of combined experience in Data Science, R&D and Engineering. Initiated, managed and delivered over 40 artificial intelligence and digital transformation products globally across manufacturing and financial industries with overall economic benefit >\$20mln.

Portfolio: https://dzorikhin.github.io/portfolio/ GitHub: https://github.com/DZorikhin

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dmitry-zorikhin/

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Digital & Al Product Delivery Manager

Jan 2022 - present

Emirates Steel Arkan, Digital Centre of Excellence - Metals & Mining, Abu Dhabi, UAE

- Leading and managing the team of Data Scientists and Digital Product Delivery Specialists
- Delivering complex Digital & Al Product Portfolio with > \$10 mln business value
- Managing Corporate Reporting Portal delivery across Group companies
- Developed Digital and Data Product Delivery Framework
- Digital & Al Products delivery in collaboration with Microsoft, Google, Siemens, SAP, iBA, SAS
- · Building, deploying, and maintaining advanced analytical and machine learning models in a business setting
- Group CEO and Group CTO engagement level

Skills: Stakeholder Management & Engagement | Product Management | Leadership | Al domain knowledge | Jira

Digital & Al Product Delivery Expert

May 2021 - Dec 2021

PwC Malta, Digital Transformation – Financial Services, Malta

- Developed and automated financial statements data extraction tool, processed over 10,000 documents
- Initiated 3 artificial intelligence projects within Assurance and Tax departments

Skills: Stakeholder Management & Engagement | Product Management | Team Leadership | Al domain knowledge

Digital & Al Product Delivery Expert

July 2020 - March 2021

NLMK Group, Digital Transformation - Metals & Mining, Yekaterinburg, Russia

- Managed 4 digital products at MVP/production stage with \$400,000/year overall economic benefit
- Created portfolio with 15 digital and data science products according with Company strategy goals
- Led the group of 6 Data Science contractor teams
- Initiated 2 innovative projects for production upgrade (laser cutting technology, hydrostatic pressure monitoring)

Skills: Stakeholder Management & Engagement | Product Management | Jira | Al domain knowledge

Data Scientist June 2019 – July 2020

Advisor Energy, Digital Transformation - Oil & Gas, Houston, USA

- Developed data-driven forecasting model for shale oil & gas production with 95% accuracy
- Prepared 8 US oil & gas shale basin reports covering over 80 E&P assets using quarterly updated data
- Data-driven Net Asset Value models | Type/Decline curves analytics | Reserves | Completions

Skills: Python | JavaScript | Classical ML | RNN | Timeseries analysis | AWS | SQL | Power BI | Git | Docker

Lead Data Analyst March 2019 – June 2019

 ${\sf SKB}\ Kontur,\ Business\ Analytics-Software\ Development,\ Yekaterinburg,\ Russia}$

• Saved \$40,000/month as the result of notification services analysis of lead company's product Kontur.Extern

Engineer Nov 2015 – March 2019

Sakhalin Energy Investment Company Ltd. (Shell and Gazprom JV) - Oil & Gas, Yuzhno-Sakhalinsk, Russia

- Saved \$2mIn/well by optimizing well completion timing execution using engineering data model database
- Initiated and got financial approval for joint cloud-based data project for Wells and Subsurface departments
- Reduced CAPEX worth \$50,000/well by optimizing completion string for workover projects

Data and Research Scientist

Nov 2009 – Aug 2014

Ural Federal University | Labfer Ltd. - Science (Optoelectronics, Physics), Yekaterinburg, Russia

- Won and led own grant for scientific research with total amount of funds over \$13,000
- Developed ferroelectric substrates bonding technology for engineering project execution worth \$260,000
- Patent owner "Hysteresis-free High-Temperature Precise Bimorph Actuators" as part of project team

EDUCATION

MSc Offshore Oil and Gas Engineering Diploma with Distinction, Robert Gordon University, Aberdeen, UK	2014 – 2015
PhD studies in Computational Physics and Physics of Condensed Matter Physics Department, Ural Federal University, Yekaterinburg, Russia	2013 – 2014
MSc of Engineering and Technology in Innovations Diploma with Distinction, Physics Department, Ural Federal University, Yekaterinburg, Russia	2011 – 2013
BSc of Engineering and Technology in Innovations Physics Department, Ural Federal University, Yekaterinburg, Russia	2007 – 2011

SKILLS, ADDITIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS AND RELEVANT CERTIFICATES